Mater and the Ghostlight is a animation, comedy,
family film directed by John Lasseter.
Mater, the rusty but trusty tow truck from Cars, spends a day in
Radiator Springs playing scary pranks on his fellow townsfolk.
That night at Flo's V8 Café, the Sheriff tells the story of the legend of the Ghostlight, and as
everyone races home Mater is left alone primed for a good old-fashioned scare.
Mater (voice), played by Larry the Cable Guy.
Lightning McQueen (voice), played by Owen Wilson.
Sally Carrera (voice), played by Bonnie Hunt.
Doc Hudson (voice), played by Paul Newman.
Sheriff (voice), played by Michael Wallis.
Ramone (voice), played by Cheech Marin.
Mater and the Ghostlight is a 2006 American animated short film released as a special feature on the DVD of
Pixar's film Cars, which was released in the United States and Canada on November 7, 2006.
The short, set in the Cars world, tells a story of Mater
being haunted by a mysterious blue light.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.